<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on JPL BLOG</title>
    <link>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on JPL BLOG</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.jpl.design/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Violinist</title>
      <link>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/machine-learning-for-the-arts/violinist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/machine-learning-for-the-arts/violinist/</guid>
      <description>Violinist  UPDATE: The name of the project has changed to Guitarist!
 Violinist enables user to play violin (or potentially any type of instrument) by just posing as they are playing it. This simple have-a-try project is based on p5.js, ml5.js, and poseNet, and help us understand the basic use of poseNet and p5.serialControl. Here&amp;rsquo;s the link to p5 web app (p5.serialControl and Arduino required).
poseNet() in p5.js The goal is to have the webcam and p5 web app be able to distinguish the relaxing, prepared, and playing status with poseNet().</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readings</title>
      <link>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/biotechnology/readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/biotechnology/readings/</guid>
      <description>CRISPR  This is a quick note of CRISPR, a topic to familiarize and workshop in class.
 CRISPR is changing how we do science. (Phillip Sharp)
 What Clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats is a family of DNA sequences found within the genomes of prokaryotic organisms such as bacteria and archaea.
Cas9 (CRISPR-associated protein 9) is an enzyme that uses CRISPR sequences as a guide to recognize and cleave specific strands of DNA that are complementary to the CRISPR sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>itSeez3D</title>
      <link>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/performative-avatars/itseez3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/performative-avatars/itseez3d/</guid>
      <description>itSeez3D This week I scanned my whole body with itSeez3D app and Occipital’s Structure Sensor for capturing color and structure information. The app did a decent job for well capturing overall information including my height (a little taller) and body shape; and details from the words on my t-shirt to acne on my face.
My partner held the iPad and scanned me for 3 times while the first trail was a total failure and we didn&amp;rsquo;t keep it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>aPPle!</title>
      <link>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/machine-learning-for-the-arts/apple/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/machine-learning-for-the-arts/apple/</guid>
      <description>aPPle! 🍎🥮🐟🍊🍳🍞🍗🍔🍟🥔🍚🥘💣
aPPle! is a webcam game powered by p5.js and ml5.js. In the game, various kinds of food will fly into the screen and the player need to choose only healthy food, that helps to lose weight, to eat. The player also need to dodge bombs flying into the screen from time to time. Office chair with wheels is recommended to use for playing. Here&amp;rsquo;s the link to play on p5 web editor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Glance of AI</title>
      <link>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/machine-learning-for-the-arts/a-glance-of-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/machine-learning-for-the-arts/a-glance-of-ai/</guid>
      <description>A Glance of AI How to say Hi in Klingonese?  In this section a task and corresponding AI system will be designed.
 Klingonese is an artificial alien language, every word of which is well documented and can be easily looked up by Star Trek fans. But when we&amp;rsquo;re faced with real Aliens, in like 100 years, we&amp;rsquo;ll have to listen to languages we&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of before. We&amp;rsquo;ll know nothing about the vocabulary, grammar, or structure, and we&amp;rsquo;ll have no family or root languages to compare to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ImageNet</title>
      <link>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/machine-learning-for-the-arts/imagenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/machine-learning-for-the-arts/imagenet/</guid>
      <description>ImageNet The first thing that amazed me was that the project of ImageNet took full advantage of WordNet and benefited from Mechanical Turk. In this way, the data is so organized by synonym sets and, sounds crazy, human-annotated. The data can be looked up easily through treemap visualization.
While each syntex, as claimed, has more than 1000 images on average to be illustrated, I still found some weak portions. With only 138 picture for People section, a lot of subdivisions, including business people and lobby boy, have no photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I, Avatar</title>
      <link>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/performative-avatars/i-avatar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.jpl.design/posts/performative-avatars/i-avatar/</guid>
      <description>I, Avatar Hundreds of Avatar making softwares are there for tuning our digital representations as the expectations. Specialized softwares like Adobe Fuse and MakeHuman; Sculpting softwares like Cinema4D and blender; Social media like Facebook and twitter; Mobile apps like Memoji and Kapu&amp;hellip;
Here I used Fuse (beta) and Kapu, a newly released app by Tencent (the largest game company on the planet), created two very distinguishable Avatars of me, and analyzed the differences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>